Welcome to our training on the brand analytics repeat purchase behavior report.
Brands enrolled in Amazon Brand Registry enjoy access to a suite of additional
selling benefits including the brand analytics tool in Seller Central.
In this
video we'll review the features and functionality of one of the reports
you'll find in brand analytics.
Repeat purchase behavior.
This report helps
brands understand how frequently customers buy their products if they've
purchased them more than once.
It can help them assess and respond to customer
engagement or they can use it to understand how satisfied customers are
with their products.
You can access the repeat purchase behavior report and
others in the brand analytics tool if you're a seller internal to a brand
enrolled in brand registry.
Simply select brands in the main menu in Seller Central
then click brand analytics or click all brand benefits then locate the brand
analytics card.
For more information about access to brand analytics and other
brand registry tools see our modules in Seller University about requesting or
managing access to brand selling benefits.
After accessing the brand
analytics tool you can select repeat purchase behavior from the list of
reports at the top of the screen.
The report lists each of your brands
according to the total number of orders received across all products.
It captures
your sales as well as the sales of other sellers listing your products.
The brand
with the most customer orders appears at the top with all other brands in
descending order below.
In the row for each brand you'll see the total number of
orders along with a series of metrics.
Repeat-ordered product sales are sales
from customers who've purchased products more than once.
For example a
customer buys a soccer ball that's part of your brand for $10 then buys two more
of the same soccer balls in a separate order for $8 each.
The repeat sales for
the soccer ball in this scenario would be $16.
You'll see the total repeat sales
for each brand.
You'll also see two related percentages change versus prior
period and percent share of total sales.
Change versus prior period is the
difference in repeat sales for a brand compared to the previous reporting period.
For example if your brand has $150 in repeat sales for the current week and
had $75 in repeat sales last week the difference in the change versus prior
period column would be 100 percent because repeat sales doubled from one
week to the next.
Percent share of total sales is the amount in repeat sales for
a brand divided by its total sales.
For example if the repeat sales for your
brand for the current week is $150 and total sales is $450 the percent share
of total sales would be 33.33 percent.
In the next set of columns repeat
ordered units you'll see similar metrics with a focus on the number of units sold
rather than the amount in sales.
For example if a customer buys a soccer ball
that's part of your brand then buys two more of the same soccer balls in a
separate order the number of units from repeat orders would be two.
You'll see
the total number of units associated with repeat orders.
Like with sales you'll
also see a change versus prior period and percent share of total units.
For
example if the total number of units associated with repeat purchases of your
brand is 20 for the current week and you had 10 units associated with repeat
purchases last week the difference you'd see in the change versus prior period
column would be 100 percent because the number of units doubled from one week to
the next.
If the number of units associated with repeat purchases of your
brand for the current week is 20 and the total number of units sold is 100 the
percent share of total sales would be 20 percent.
In the next set of columns
repeat customer count you'll see similar metrics about the number of
customers who purchased your brand's products more than once.
For example
three customers purchased your soccer ball one ordered a single soccer ball
one time another ordered two soccer balls then two more in a separate order and a
third ordered three soccer balls then two more and then four more in separate
orders.
The total number of repeat customers in this scenario would be two
you'll see the total number of repeat customers for a brand along with a
change versus prior period which follows the same basic formula used in previous
columns for repeat sales and units.
For example if the total number of
customers associated with repeat purchases of your brand is 10 for the
current week and you had five last week you'd see 100 percent in the change
versus prior period column because the number of repeat customers doubled from
one week to the next.
In the last set of columns repeat customer share you'll see
two additional percentages percent share of total customers is the number of
repeat customers for the brand listed in the previous column divided by the number
of unique customers for the brand and change versus prior period is the
difference in the percentage of repeat customers compared to the previous
reporting period.
For example if the number of customers associated with
repeat purchases of your brand is 10 for the current week and the total number of
unique customers is 40 the percent share of total customers would be 25% if the
percent share of total customers last week had been 20 percent the change
versus prior period would be five percent.
When you first access the repeat
purchase behavior report it'll be defaulted to show metrics for each of your
brands for the previous week.
You can click ASIN view at the top of the
report to view the same metrics at the product level.
Use this view to better
understand repeat purchases within a brand.
Back on the brand View section of
the report you can use the drop-down menus at the top to view a specific time
period.
When doing so keep in mind that data is generally available in brand
analytics within 72 hours.
After selecting a time period click the apply
button to refresh the report.
You can also use filters to narrow the report to a
specific brand.
Click show filters then use the drop-down menu to select a
brand.
Click the refine results button to refresh the report.
If you'd like to add
or remove columns on the repeat purchase behavior report click customize columns
on the right hand side then check or uncheck boxes in the pop-up.
Click the
save button to return to the updated report.
To download a copy of the report
click the generate download button then in the pop-up select either simple view
to download the report you see on screen or select comprehensive view to
download the report with all relevant columns.
Click the generate download
button to start your download which you can monitor by accessing the download
manager.
Finally if you want more information about how a specific metric
is calculated click metrics glossary to see a set of comprehensive definitions.
On the metrics glossary page you can expand each section to see additional
details.
We encourage brands to use all the features and functionality of the
repeat purchase behavior report to get insights into their performance in the
Amazon store.
Use it to understand customer engagement for your brand how
often customers re-engage with products or use repeat purchases to gauge
customer satisfaction what they buy enjoy and decide to buy again.
This
concludes our overview of the repeat purchase behavior report.
If you'd like
step-by-step instructions for other brand analytics reports see our series of
modules in Seller University.
Thank you and happy selling in the Amazon store.